Samuel Lalley

in Samuel Lalley | Samuellalley@gmail.com | CalleyDev

Summary

I am a recent graduate with a B.S. in Nuclear Engineering and experience in software development, UI/UX design, and machine learning. I am interested in working in the field of software development. I am passionate about writing clean, efficient code and improving user experiences. I have a strong drive to do things correctly and continue learning. Additionally, my work experiences have reinforced the importance of contributing to a supportive team environment while also independently managing tasks.

SKILLS

Java	Linux	Server Management	MCNP
Python	Git	Typescript	Machine Learning
С#	Secure Shell (SSH)	Javascript	Radiation Physics
Bash	Docker	Powershell	Radiation Detection

Work Experience

Engineering Associate - Renaissance Code Development

January 2023 - Present

Developed new features and bug fixes for PIMAL and Varskin software. Integrated and built the UI for Extravasation module. Wrote technical documentation for software release. Restructured and manage internal version control. Promoted from Engineering Technician to Engineering Associate upon graduation.

Nuclear Engineering Research Assistant - Oregon State University March 2022 - June 2024

- Wrote machine learning nuclide identification model to train on synthetically generated medical nuclide data from MCNP with the goal of identifying the nuclides on a real detector.
- Researched correlations between background radiation and weather patterns using statistical analysis.
- Modeled a lab scale city design in MCNP and wrote Python code to automate generation of MCNP decks with different source locations and graphically display the resulting data.

Barista - Starbucks

March 2019 - September 2022

EDUCATION

2021 - 2024	Oregon State University - Bachelor of Science Nuclear Engineering	(GPA: 3.56)
2018 - 2021	Linn Benton Community College - Associate of Science in Engineering	(GPA: 3.54)

Projects and Accomplishments

UI/UX Evaluation of Digital Simulators - Senior Design Project of the Year

Conducted UI/UX research on NuScale's reactor simulator to improve usability for Gen Z users. Provided data-driven recommendations to enhance user interaction and efficiency.

Home Server Administration

Designed, built, and manage a Proxmox-based server hosting multiple services, including a local AI security system, a VPN Tunnel, and a DNS server.

Eagle Scout 2017

Led a team to design and build a bike shelter for Jackson Street Youth Services in Corvallis, Oregon.